THUTA LIN

Software Developer



+601112294400



thutalin1727@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/thuta-lin

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Monash University Malaysia Jul 2017 – Oct 2021

Foundation Studies in Engineering

Curtin University Malaysia Feb 2016 – Dec 2016

SKILLS

Angular

React

JavaScript & TypeScript

HTML & CSS

Ionic Framework

Git & CI/CD

SQL, PostgreSQL & MongoDB

Python

Java

Node.js (Express)

AWS

SUMMARY

Passionate and motivated individual with one and a half year of experience in building reliable and performant enterprise applications in the industry. Primarily used **Angular Framework** and **React Library** to build front-end applications for the web, and **Ionic Framework** to provide hybrid mobile solutions. Actively pursuing the goal of becoming a professional full-stack developer by learning **Java Spring Framework**.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Developer / Feb 2022 - Present

BigLedger Sdn Bhd / Malaysia

- Worked in an agile team of 3 handling multiple clients, and successfully helped and delivered 2 of our clients projects.
- Specialized in developing new features, components, and widgets for Cross-Platform Ecommerce project, built and developed using lonic Framework with Angular to support across different platforms.
- Built micro-frontend applications, using **Angular**, for the company's SaaS platform and refactor on state management of these applications.
- Implemented integration with popular e-commerce platforms such as Shopify, Shopee, Lazada, etc. and built a consolidated UI workflow that supports managing orders and products to various platforms from our system.
- Assisted newcomers with onboarding and briefing on Cross-Platform
 Ecommerce project overview, workflow, coding standards and practices.
- Performed rigorous code review on changes introduced to the project for quality assurance.
- Introduced to Reactive Programming and completed the following courses: RxJS, NgRx, and Angular from Ultimate Courses as part of the company's on-boarding process.

Software Engineer Intern / Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

Juris Technologies Sdn Bhd / Malaysia

- Worked on debt collection & recovery system and primaryily involved in testing features, UI enhancement and perform fixes using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Used PHP and SQL, to resolve backend issues and SQL query performed by the internal framework, used by the company.
- Reported bugs and logical errors present in the code due to the coupling between the user interface and business logic.